Guide to the Dell Williams papers, 1922-2008.
Williams, Dell papers, 1922-2008
- Series II. Colleagues, Correspondents, and Subjects
  - Sexuality
    - Lowry, Thomas, The Classic Clitoris author; also corresp. w/ D.W., circa 1975-1983 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Maines, Rachel, 2002, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Masturbation and female sex articles, 1975-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - McCormick, Charles G., "Healthy Sex." NYU professor and acquaintance of Dell's., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Miller, Sally, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miss Vera: Cross-Dress for Success, Amazing Grace (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - New Paltz clippings, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ogden, Gina, 2002, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Ogden, Gina--Building Bridges ITCR workshop 2004 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - PC muscle articles, female orgasm articles (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - PC muscle (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - PC muscle, Kegel (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - P.K. correspondence regarding sexuality workshops (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Prelude 3" brochure (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Princeton Center for Behavioral Consultation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Princeton Center for Behavioral Consultation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Reich, Wilhelm--book discussion through the Humanist Foundation (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Reich, Wilhelm's "Listen, Little Man!" 1945 typescript. Typed in 1950's by Dell Zetlin (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Reinisch, June M. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Resnick, Stella (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Revolting Behavior" conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Rice-Mandigo, Linda: Emotional Coding (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Robinson: Research on "Trigger Spot" (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Routledge: Taylor and Francis Group: Sex Education, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - SAGE (Senior Action in a Gay Environment), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Schubach, Gary (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Searcy, Mickie--Redmon, George Sensual for Life, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Sexuality (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Sexuality Research and Social Policy (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Sexuality Workshops, 1992, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Annie Sprinkle (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Society for the Scientific Study of Sexuality (SSSS), 2003, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Steps for Recovery newsletter, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - "Still Doing It: The Intimate Lives of Women over 65" (film), 2004 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Strossen, Nadine: "A Feminist Critique of 'The' Feminist Critique of Pornography", draft, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Sue Swift (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sundahl, Deborah, Female Ejaculation and the G-spot. (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - The Technology of Orgasm (film based on book by Rachel Maines), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Vibrator articles and booklets, 1973-1988, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Whipple, Beverly (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Whipple, Beverly, bibliography (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Written Out: A Panel Challenging Attacks on Women's Sexuality" flyer, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Xandria Collection (sex store) (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Spirituality
    - Aromatherapy Class (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Ballentine, Rudolph--Radical Healing (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clark, Lana: Tantra, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Clark, Lana: Tantra, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Clark, Lana: Tantra, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Clark-Yasuda, Lana, "Sexual Dysfunctioning" (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Counseling (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Dramer, Joel; Alstad, Diana; White, Ganga, The Guru Papers, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Fabian Cosi (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - FIONS e-Newsletter, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - FreedomWorks, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Goddess tours & articles (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Graci, Lori: "Ecstatic Breathing" (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Harvey, Andrew: Spiritual Activism (film), 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Hession, Jim, Love is an Intention: An Interview with Jerry Jud about the Principles and Skills of Loving (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - International Institute for Bioenergetic Analysis, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - "4th International Womyn's Festival of the Healing Arts" brochure, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Mazur, Ron, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Monaghan, Patricia, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Mysteries of the Bible--Sodom/Gomorrah, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Morgan, Brenda (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Pagoda Temple of Love, a lesbian spiritual and cultural community, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Progressive Women's Spiritual Association (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Progressive Women's Spiritual Association (PWSA), 1992 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Quoduoshka (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ramsdale, David and Ellen: Energy-Ecstacy Workshop, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Rev. Goddess Charmaine, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Sánchez, Rebecca, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Sexuality and Spirituality Workshops (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Shakti Cheryll (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Shalom Mountain, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Shalom Mountain Retreat (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Sivananda Yoga Camp Retreat (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Slinger, Penny: Tantra Workshops (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Spirituality, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Stone, Merlin and goddess tours, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Tantra, circa 1995-2005 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Unity Center of NYC, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - The Women's Well: Course offerings, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - WiseWoman Healing Ways (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Womongathering (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Womonspeak: FIRE: Womongathering's Newsletter, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Feminism and Other
    - Bettye, book inscriptions from (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Borysenko, Joan; Lawrence, Eliz.; Maier, Jan--Gathering of Women Retreat, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Budoff, Penny Wise and Judith Barr (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Burton, Christine and Golden Threads (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Ceballos, Jacqui, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Corwin, Norman "Document A/777" (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Daly, Mary--Defense Fund (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Dance and Body Image (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Derry - note from inside Dell's copy of "Eunuchs for the Kingdom of Heaven", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Feminist Files (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Feminist Institute (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Feminists for Freedom of Expression, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 75-76)
    - Institute for Feminist Studies (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Invitation to Money-Making Venture (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Goldberg, Merle, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Hite, Shere, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Horan, Pat--Mother-themed poetry (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Kennedy, Flo memorial, January 2001 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Lesbians through the Ages--dance party, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Luxemburg, Rosa and Zetkin, Clara--postcard, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Maginnis, Pat--Political cartoons (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - "Matrix" brochures [retirement community for women] (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mehlman's guide to female periodicals, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Sally--Writings, circa 1956-1998 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Millett, Kate, 1998, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Moonheart Places: Urban Goddesses Parties (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - National Organization for Women-New York City, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - National Women's Hall of Fame, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - NCAC: National Coalition Against Censorship, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - New York Society for Ethical Culture, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Reitz, Rosetta: Menopause (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Rice-Mandigo, Linda - note from inside Dell's copy of Emma Morgan's "Gooseflesh" (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Seaman, Barbara (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - USPS Women's Rights Stamp Image, Betty Lane, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Veteran Feminists of America, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Visible magazine (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - War Resisters' League (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Weisstein, Naomi - remarks by Jesse Lemisch, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Women and Pornography; Prostitution Conferences, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Women/Feminism Misc. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Writers' Workshops, Publishers, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Series III. Clippings and Print Material
  - Clitoris articles (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Women/Feminism articles (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Sex and Love, articles about (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Sexuality articles (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Sexuality articles (newsprint), 1974- (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sexuality articles, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sexuality articles, 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sexuality articles (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Spirituality clippings, various (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
  - Brochures and clippings, sexuality events., 1996-2006 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Miscellaneous print material (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Alstad, Diana, interview with: "Abortion, Power, and the Morality Wars", 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Barbara Louise, "The Problem is Privilege" (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Ben-David, Joseph, "The Historical Development of Humanism as a Religion of the Future", 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Big Mama Rag, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Broadside: A Feminist Review, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Brooklyn Daily Eagle, reprint of December 30, 1900 edition (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Catalogs: Vibratex (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Circumcision articles, 1998, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "The Daughters Cycle: Electra Speaks" by Clare Coss, Sondra Segal and Roberta Sklar--Union Seminary Quarterly Review, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - "The Effect of Hysterectomy on Sexual Functioning"--Annual Review of Sex Research, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Ellis, Albert, "How to Maintain and Enhance Your Rational-Emotive Therapy Gains", 1984 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Ensler, Eve, The Vagina Monologues, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - "Everything a Happily Married Bible Belt Woman Always Wanted to Know about Sex...", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "The Forces of Love, Eros, and Sex" (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Fragments of a System of Psychology of Sexual Life" (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gaian Voices, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Haas, Emanuel, and Dan, "Lesbian and Heterosexual Relationships Across the Female Lifecourse" (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "He Who Laughs Lasts"--AARP magazine (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Hot Flash: Newsletter for Midlife and Older Women, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Isis (goddess), information about (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Iverson, Lucille,Outrage (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Jordan, June, "A New Politics of Sexuality", 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Journal of Sacred Feminine Wisdom, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Keller, Dolores, Applied Sex Therapy: Solving Sexual Problems and Dysfunctions, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Lewinsky, Monica (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - "The Lily" (Reprint of 1852 feminist newsletter) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Masturbation" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Meditation (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Middendorf, Ilse, "The Meaning of Breathing" (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Sally, The ABCs of Living Without Cancer, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Miller, Sally--sexuality articles, circa 1987-1993 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Moolaadé (movie), article about (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nagle, Jill, article about lesbians and dildos refers to Eve's Garden. From On our backs., June/July 1998 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Nelson, James, "Needed: A Continuing Sexual Revolution", 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - NOW booklet: "The Future Is Revolution", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - On our backs, calendar., 2002 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Patent, Arnold, "The Mutual Support Group Handout" (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Petersen, James, "The Sex of Joy" (Playboy) (Eve's Garden mentioned in article), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Pittenger, Norman, Time for Consent (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - The Progressive Woman's Quarterly: "On The Issues", Summer 1996 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Pushkin, Alexander (supposedly)--Secret Journal of, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Reich, Wilhelm (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - "Sexual Secrets" (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - She Who Dwells Within, review of--Rabbi Lynn Gottlieb (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Spirituality and Sexuality, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Steinem Blames White Male Dominance for Church Sex Scandal, 9-11", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Taki's Top Drawer" newspaper article, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - True Health, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Vance, Carole, "More Danger, More Pleasure", 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Wilhelm Reich vs. the U.S.A." (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Wise Woman, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - The Wit and Wisdom of May West (Box 3, Folder 123)
- Series IV. Audiovisual Material
  - "Veronica Vera's Portrait of a Sexual Evolutionary", v. 710; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - "Electroluxury: A New Twist On Domestic Bliss" Directed by Teri Rice, v. 711; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - "500 Unusual Sex Practices", v. 712; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - "Increasing Male Sexual Potency", v. 713; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - "Sensual Pleasuring", v. 723; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - Eichel, Ed, "Sexual Dysfunction", v. 724; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - Dell Williams at Whole Life Expo Sexuality Workshop, March 20, 2004; v. 840; VHS videotape (Box 8)
  - Dell Williams interview tape #1, 2002-07-01; v. 11002; Mini DV tape (Box 8)
  - Dell Williams interview tape #2, 2002-07-01; v. 11003; Mini DV tape (Box 8)
  - ...[?] Workshop, tr. 8026a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Sheri Hite Interview", tr. 8028a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Male Sex Interview/Men--Greater Virility", tr. 8031a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "NOW Eastern regional conference: Betty Friedan, Shirley Chisholm", February 11-12, 1972; tr. 8033a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - NOW Eastern regional conference, February 12-13, 1972; tr. 8034a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - NOW: Comm...[?] Sexuality; (other side)"Is there sex after fem...?", August 30, 1973; tr. 8024a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Queens College Women's Festival NOW, March 23, 1977, 8 PM; tr. 8022a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Int'l Women's Day: Lesbian Indian [?]; (other side)Barry Farber, et al., March 8, 1975; April 10, 1972; tr. 8020a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Union Sq. Rally, Int'l Women's Day, March 8, 1975; tr. 8021a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Sapphic Journeys", 1980; tr. 8038a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Enjoying Sex with Safety, by Isadora Alman", 1987; tr. 8032a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Sex Between Equals, tr. 8015a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - Gloria Steinem, Princeton, tr. 8035a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Society for Scientific Study of Sex + Sado-Masochism Conference: Lesbian S+M and Anal Fistfucking", tr. 8030a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Freeing the Female Orgasm, by Charles and Caroline Muir, sides 1 and 2", tr. 8040a; Cassette audiotape (Box 8)
  - "Freeing the Female Orgasm, sides 3 and 4", tr. 8041a; Cassette audiotape (Box 8)
  - "Hot Women Talk Tapes", tr. 8076a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Lipstick and Lace", tr. 8077a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "QUADS--Female Sexuality", tr. 8048a; Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
  - "Marilyn Volker", tr. 8050a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - "Marilyn Volker", tr. 8051a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - "Finding the Common Ground: Exploring Issues of Intimacy and Sexuality", tr. 8052a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - "Relationship Failure: A successful case of resistance", tr. 8061a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - "Keynote Address: Listening to Our Bodies", tr. 8062a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - AASECT XX Annual Conference, NYC: "P4 Debate: Sexuality and Feminism: Betty Friedan and Barbara Ehrenreicht", 1987; tr. 8063a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - AASECT XXIV Annual Conference: "Plenary: Bullough, Vern L., Ph.D., R.N., Sexology and the Future of Sex", 1992; tr. 8064a; Cassette audiotape; inside Eros and Psyche Conference binder (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Ford, Dr. Helen: Combining the Creative Powers of Sexual and Spiritual Energies," tape 1, 1991; tr. 8053a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Ford, Dr. Helen: Combining the Creative Powers of Sexual and Spiritual Energies," tape 2, 1991; tr. 8054a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Ford, Dr. Helen: Combining the Creative Powers of Sexual and Spiritual Energies," tape 3, 1991; tr. 8055a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Oken, Alan, Current Transformations in the Evolution of Consciousness", 1991; tr. 8056a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Gage, Suzann, R.N., Feminist Researchers Redefine the Clitoris and Women's Sexuality", 1991; tr. 8057a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Oken, Alan, The Horoscope: The Soul and The Peronality--A Day of Astrological Sharings", tape 2, 1991; tr. 8058a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Oken, Alan, The Horoscope: The Soul and The Peronality--A Day of Astrological Sharings", tape 3, 1991; tr. 8059a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Oken, Alan, The Horoscope: The Soul and The Peronality--A Day of Astrological Sharings", tape 4, 1991; tr. 8060a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Wadel, Stephanie, Spiritual Sexuality--The Quodoushka Cherokee Way", 1991; tr. 8065a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Isenberg, Elliott, Ph.D., The Association Between the Feminine, Sexuality and Evil", 1991; tr. 8066a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Sovatsky, Stuart C. ,Ph.D., Gender Worship in the Erotic Mystery", 1991; tr. 8067a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Ford, Dr. Helen, Love and Sex--The Causes and Potential Helaers of Illness", 1991; tr. 8068a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Juhan, Deane, The Erogenous Organism: The Anatomy and Neurology of Human Sexual Response", 1991; tr. 8069a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Grace, Lori, Tantra: A Path to Bliss", 1991; tr. 8070a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Casey, Caroline, The Ancient Future of Erotic Paradigm", 1991; tr. 8071a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Eros and Psyche Conference: "Voigt, Harrison, Ph.D., Tantrism and Intimacy: Enriching the Sexual Experience of Couples", 1991; tr. 8072a; Cassette audiotape (Box 6)
  - Tantric Loving-Courses for Conscious Lovers: Interview with Stewart Esposito, Cassette audiotape (Box 7)
- Series V. Merchandise
  - Antique Electric Vibrator, from the P.A. Geier Co., [circa 1911-1920] (Box 4)
  - Hartman, Bunne--Prints (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Feminist Memorabilia: Buttons: Shirley Chisholm, Flo Kennedy, Clara de Miha (Box 2)
  - Bullet Vibrator (Box 2)
  - Dildo: Scorpio Rising (Box 2)
  - APD (Anal Pleasurable Device/Butt Plug) (Box 2)
  - Leather Harness (Box 2)
  - Rotating Dildo (Box 2)
  - Vibrator (Box 2)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Publications and Videos Removed From Collection 7676 - cataloged as individual items and serials in the Human Sexuality Collection (multiple issues of periodicals are denoted by parentheses):
Adams, Florence. Mushy Eggs. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1973.
Alcott, Louisa May. Rose in Bloom. Chicago: The John C. Winston Company, 1933.
Allen, Gina and Clement G. Martin. Intimacy: Sensitivity, Sex, and the Art of Love, 1971.
Anderlini-D'Onofrio, Serena. Plural loves: designs for bi and poly living. New York: Harrington Park Press, 2004.
Annual Review of Sex Research. v.14, 2003.
April, K. and W.E. Schreiner. The Condom: No Guarantee Against AIDS. Sheffield, Great Britain: Quentin Publications, 1992.
Australian Women's Forum, 2 issues.
Avant Garde: Picasso's Erotic Gravures. Issue #8, New York.
Baehr, Ninia. Abortion without Apology: a radical history for the 1990's. Boston: South End Press, 1990.
Barbach, Lonnie. Shared Intimacies: Women's Sexual Experiences. Garden City, NY: Anchor Press/Doubleday, 1980.
Barry, Kathleen. Female Sexual Slavery. New York: Avon Books, 1979.
Beauvoir, Simone de. The Second Sex. New York: Vintage Books, 1989.
Bingham, Sallie. Passion and Prejudice: A Family Memoir. New York: Applause Books, 1991.
Bishop, Clifford. Sex & Spirit. Alexandria, VA: Time-Life Books, 1996.
Bishop, Clifford. Sex and Spirit: An Illustrated Guide to Sacred Sexuality. Berkeley: Seastone, 1996.
Blank, Joani. Good Vibrations: The Complete Woman's Guide to Vibrators. Burlingame, CA: Down There Press, 1976.
Body of Art. v.1 issue B, October 1996.
Boyd, Billy Ray. Circumcision: What it Does. San Francisco: Taterhill Press, 1990.
Britton, Patti, Ph.D. The Adventures of HER in France. Beverly Hills: Leopard Rising, n.d.
Brown, Rita Mae. Dolley: A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War. New York: Bantam Books, 1994.
Bullough, Vern. Sexual Attitudes: myths & realities. Amherst, NY: Prometheus Books, 1995
Calderone, Mary S. Talking with your Child About Sex. New York: Ballantine Books, 1982.
Caprio, Frank S. Variations in Sexual Behavior. New York: Grover Press, Inc., 1955
Cawthorne, Nigel. Secrets of Love: The Erotic Arts Through the Ages. 1997.
Chalker, Rebecca. A Woman's Book of Choices: Abortion, Menstrual Extraction, RU-486. New York: Four Walls Eight Windows, 1992.
Chernin, Kim and Renate Stendhal. Sex and Other Sacred Games: Love, Desire, Power, and Possession. New York: Times Books, 1989.
Chopin, Kate. The Awakening. New York: Bantam Books, 1988.
Clardy, Andrea Fleck. Words to the wise: a writer's guide to feminist and lesbian periodicals & publishers. Ithaca: Firebrand Books, 1986.
Colton, Helen. Sex After the Sexual Revolution. New York: Association Press, 1972.
Common Ground: The Sex Issue, issue 116, Summer 2003.
Congdon, Kirby. Dream-work. Brooklyn: Cycle Press, 1970. (autographed to Dell by author)
Congdon, Kirby. Dream-Work. New York: Ralph Simmons, Jr., 1970.
Daly, Mary. Beyond God the Father: toward a philosophy of women's liberation. Boston: Beacon Press, 1973.
Douglas, Claire. The woman in the mirror: analytical psychology and the feminine. Boston: Sigo Press, 1990.
Douglas, Nik and Penny Slinger. Mountain Ecstasy. New York: Dragon's Dream Ltd., 1978.
Duffy, Yvonne. ...all things are possible. Ann Arbor, MI: AJ Garvin & Associates, 1981.
Ecstasy: the nonsexist erotic journal. Spring 1976. Half Moon Bay, CA: New Time Press.
Edwardes, Allen and R.E.L. Masters. The Cradle of Erotica: A Study of Afro-Asian Sexual Expression and an Analysis of Erotic Freedom in Social Relationships. New York: Bell Publishing Company, 1962.
Eidos v.8 no.4, n.d.; also article from one issue: "RENE: Art, Sex, Religion and Censorship."
Elder, Rob and Sarah. Crash. New York: Atheneum, 1977. (about a plane crash that Dell's brother Lorenzo Zetlin was in; he is mentioned on page 69)
Ellis, Albert. The Art and Science of Love. New York: Lyle Stuart, 1960.
Ellis, Dr. Albert. The Sensuous Person, 1974.
Erotic Art by Living Artists, printed by Artwork Press, 1992.
Federation of Feminist Women's Health Centers. How to Stay Out of the Gynecologist's Office. Hollywood, CA: Women to Women Publications, 1986
Feminist Bookstore News. San Francisco, CA. (3)
Gay & Lesbian Review Worldwide, The. v.10 no.3.
Gershick, Zsa Zsa. Gay Old Girls. Los Angeles: Alyson Books, 1998.
Girlfriends. 1995:May/June.
Goldsmith, Barbara. Other Powers: The Age of Suffrage, Spiritualism, and the Scandalous Victoria Woodhull. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1998.
Grahn, Judy. The Work of a Common Woman. Trumansburg, NY: The Crossing Press, 1978.
Griffin, Susan. Pornography and Silence: Culture's Revenge Against Nature. New York: Harper & Row, 1981.
Hanmer, Trudy. Taking a Stand Against Sexism and Sex Discrimination. New York: Franklin Watts, 1990.